Chapter 1: Life in the Village

The next morning...

The day started early for the village. Rio woke up before sunrise and made his way to the living room of the chief’s house.

“Good morning.”

“Oh my, you’re quite the early riser there. Good morning,” Yuba replied with widened eyes. She was already awake, sitting on a cushion in the living room after lighting the fireplace.

“I was thinking of helping out the villagers today with any tasks they might have. But first, could I help you make breakfast in any way?”

“Is that so? If you’re offering, then you’re more than welcome to do so. I look forward to it.”

And so, Rio and Yuba spoke for a while. Until...

“Mrrgh... Good morning, Granny...”

Ruri appeared in the living room, half-asleep and still wearing the underwear she had slept in. It was a slightly scandalous appearance for a girl of her age to be wearing before the opposite sex. Hidden beneath her underwear were limbs that emphasized her feminine softness, and plump breasts that accentuated her upper body.

“Good morning... Have you forgotten about Rio here, by any chance?” Yuba said with stifled laughter.

“...Huh? A-Ah!”

Ruri finally realized that Rio was right there. She hurriedly looked down at herself, then blushed as red as a ripe apple. Rio avoided eye contact, but she took that to mean he had caught a glimpse of her unladylike form.

“I-I’m going to change!” Ruri covered her body with both her hands and ran back to her room.

Rio gave a tired sigh. He had encountered similar situations numerous times before, back when he lived with Latifa in the spirit folk village. Fortunately, it didn’t seem like Ruri had the personality to irrationally get mad at him for it, but they would probably be awkward around each other for a little longer.

Sure enough, when Ruri returned from her room several moments later, she watched Rio from the corner of her eye.

Ah, well. I guess there’s no helping that...

Ruri was his older cousin, so Rio could honestly say that no strange feelings had risen from that. But that wasn’t the case when it came to Ruri’s point of view, because she didn’t know Rio was her younger cousin.

“So, are you any good at cooking, Rio? You offered to help with breakfast.” Yuba smiled cheerily.

“Y-Yes, please leave it to me.” Rio nodded with an embarrassed look.

“Then, let’s have you make breakfast today and see how it goes. Ruri, go with Rio to trade for breakfast ingredients and introduce him to everyone. Have the village girls get used to seeing his face around here.”

“Eh? O-Oh, okay. ...Let’s go, Rio.” Ruri hesitated for a moment, before giving an uncomfortable nod. She still seemed to be feeling humiliated about her foolishness earlier.

“Oh, and tell Sayo to come to the house with Shin. We’ll be having breakfast here,” Yuba requested.

“Yes, ma’am...” Ruri answered dully before leaving through the front door with Rio.

Their first destination was the kitchen garden behind the village chief’s home. Unlike the fields that were managed by the village, the kitchen gardens were owned by each individual house.

“Our village operates primarily on bartering and trading. The first thing we do every morning is harvest the vegetables grown in our kitchen garden. Then, we bring them to the village square and trade them with the vegetables grown by other families. That makes up the ingredients for a day’s worth of meals,” Ruri explained as they gathered the vegetables grown in the village chief’s garden. Once they were done harvesting them, they headed toward the village square.

The square was already filled with young women from the village chatting noisily with each other. They ranged from their mid-teens to late twenties in age.

“Morning, everyone!” Ruri greeted them energetically, moving to join a circle of the girls.

“Oh, Ruri. Good mor—” The girls noticed Ruri and cheerfully made to return her greeting, when they noticed the unfamiliar boy behind her and froze on the spot. Before she knew it, Ruri was getting questioning gazes from all the girls.

“Erm, this is Rio. He’s the son of one of Granny’s old acquaintances and has been traveling around the world. That’s why his clothes look a little strange. He’ll be staying at our place for a while, so I wanted to introduce him to everyone... Go on, Rio.” Ruri carefully watched the reactions of the other girls as she timidly introduced him. She then prompted him to step forward.

“Please allow me to introduce myself. My name is Rio. I have yet to acclimatize myself to life here, so I hope you can find it in your hearts to forgive any inconveniences I may cause in the future. It is a pleasure to meet you all.” Rio adopted a friendly smile as he gave his well-mannered greeting.

“Uhm... It’s nice to meet you too,” the girls replied, mildly embarrassed.

“Hey, Rio. There’s no need to use such formal language with us. Everyone gets nervous when a boy like you acts that way,” Ruri advised with a wry smile.

“Ah... I’m afraid I’m more accustomed to this form of speech. I will do my best to adjust accordingly,” Rio replied with a smile similar to Ruri’s.

The women of the village watched their exchange closely; they seemed to be feeling rather bashful in Rio’s presence. However, they all shot implicitly questioning looks in Ruri’s direction — looks that said it wasn’t fair for her to be the only one close to him.

The only men that the village girls had in their social circles were rough and rowdy, making Rio’s gentle and calm demeanor like a breath of fresh air. His handsome yet androgynous face only accentuated his allure even more.

Haha... They’re definitely going to try to pry more out of me about Rio during work later.

Ruri smiled bitterly to herself; she could feel the silent pressure coming from the girls. She glanced at Rio to see him standing somewhat uncomfortably on the receiving end of all the girls’ shy scrutiny. He shifted his gaze toward Ruri, seeking help with a troubled expression. Ruri was taken aback by the unintentional eye contact, her body shaking with a flinch.

...Hmph. He didn’t even care about how I felt before.

Ruri recalled how Rio had seen her immodest morning attire earlier and pouted her lips as she blushed. She knew that it had mostly been her own fault, though. It was obvious that taking it out on Rio here wouldn’t make the situation any better. She had mixed feelings about the storm of questions the girls would surely bombard her with later... but she just wanted to head home for now.

And so, she decided to rescue Rio.

“Come on, now, let’s get these ingredients traded already. It’s almost time for work!” Ruri snappily wrapped up the conversation and began to move around, trading for vegetables.

The girls all looked like they wanted to talk to Rio, but they couldn’t find the right timing to do so. Ruri took that as a blessing and swiftly piled the vegetables into her basket. Once she had gathered all the ones that she needed, she turned to address Rio, who happened to be the one carrying the basket.

“Okay, all done. Let’s go, Rio.” She pushed his back to prompt him to move.

“Ah, that’s right! Sayo!” Ruri turned back, remembering one last thing.

“...Huh?” Sayo was among the girls silently staring at Rio. Her body trembled with a start when her name was called, and she looked up in question.

“Granny wants you to come to our house with Shin. We’re gonna have breakfast together,” Ruri explained briefly.

“Eh... Ah, okay. Got it.” Sayo nodded timidly.

“You’ll find out what she wants when we meet, I guess. See you soon!” With those parting words, Ruri hurriedly left again. Rio gave a small bow to the slightly confused village girls and trailed after her.

◇◇◇

After the events at the village square, Rio returned to the village chief’s house and began to prepare breakfast. The village was low on dried meat and seasoning, particularly salt, so he dipped into the reserves of his Time-Space Cache to supplement his recipe. After all, there were enough ingredients and spices stored inside to last several years.

However, he hid the existence of the Time-Space Cache, as it was too troublesome to explain. He simply removed enough supplies to seem as though he’d retrieved them from his backpack instead. It was still a fairly large amount of meat and seasonings, though — enough to make Yuba happy.

“This is wonderful. Dried meat is a luxury around here, and we have very few opportunities to buy salt, so there’s never enough. Are you sure it’s all right, though? This many ingredients wouldn’t have been cheap, no?” Yuba asked hesitantly.

“I don’t mind,” Rio replied, shaking his head gently. “There’s no point in letting it go to waste, so please accept it as rent for my stay. I’m going to make breakfast with this now... Enough to serve five people, is that right?”

“Yes, Sayo and Shin will be coming later. Thank you. Ruri, go stand with him and watch.” Yuba saw them off as Rio and Ruri went to kitchen together.

Since they were going to be living together from now on, they needed to find out how good Rio’s cooking skills were. He would prepare the food alone, and Ruri would act as his judge.

“The firewood’s already been prepared — I’ll show you where later. All the kitchen tools and tableware are in that cupboard. If there’s anything else you need to know, feel free to ask.”

“Okay. What should I do about water? I can generate it with spirit arts if needed.”

“Ah, you can use the water in that jug there. Either Granny or I will use spirit arts to refill it once a day, but I guess you can use spirit arts too?” Ruri asked with raised eyebrows. Spirit arts were more commonplace than sorcery and magic in the Yagumo region, but the number of users there was fairly small.

“...Yes. So, you two can use it too...” Rio’s eyes widened a little in surprise.

“Yeah. Our family line has always had a really high aptitude for spirit arts, despite the fact that we’re commoners. That’s part of the reason why Granny’s the village chief. Other than me, Sayo and her older brother Shin also have the ability to use spirit arts, so we’ve all been learning together since we were young.”

“I see... So that’s how it is.” Rio nodded in understanding.

When compared to elves, dwarves, werebeasts, and other spirit folk, humans generally had a low aptitude for using spirit arts. However, very rarely, someone with a high aptitude for using it was born. This meant that his father, Zen, could probably use spirit arts too, Rio mused to himself. It would have been nearly impossible for his father to make the harsh journey between the Yagumo and Strahl regions without them.

Rio found that information fascinating, but he couldn’t afford to let his goal fall to the back of his mind.

After using spirit arts to light the firewood in the kitchen furnace, he began to cook. The menu included rice, miso soup, meat, and a vegetable stir fry, along with the pickled vegetables Yuba had already made.

Incidentally, there were many seasonings available in Yagumo that were reminiscent of Asian foods on Earth — including both soy sauce and miso — which made it easy for Rio to recreate the taste of Japanese food. Rio had come across all kinds of ingredients and condiments during his time in the spirit folk village, but being able to collect those he hadn’t seen before in the Yagumo region made him feel a keen sense of satisfaction.

“...Hmph. I guess you’re pretty good, Rio,” Ruri muttered absently as she watched Rio prepare the ingredients with an experienced hand.

“Thank you very much. I have to be able to do this much, since I travel alone.” Rio shook his head bashfully.

“No, no, this isn’t just some average level of skill. Your knife-handling is even better than mine.” Ruri gave a slightly conflicted smile. The two of them continued to chat idly and opened up to each other, bit by bit. Less than an hour later, they’d finished cooking all of the food.

“Look, Granny. Rio made us a delicious-smelling breakfast!” With a cheerful grin, Ruri carried the completed dishes into the living room and served them on the table.

“Oh? This certainly looks nice. It seems we’ll have no problem leaving Rio on cooking duty.” Yuba broke into a surprised smile at the sight of the dishes lining the table.

“Umm, excuse me.”

A cute feminine voice could be heard from the entrance, where the door was left wide open. There stood Sayo and a boy standing behind her; he was around Rio’s age.

“Ah, Sayo. Welcome. Come in, come in. You too, Shin.” Ruri waved the two of them inside with a smile.

“O-Okay. P-Please excuse the intrusion.” Sayo gave a polite bow and timidly stepped through the doorway.

“Yeah, excuse us.” Shin followed after her.

“Good of you two to make it — you’re just in time for breakfast. Come on up.” Yuba summoned the two of them closer as Ruri returned to the kitchen.

“Thanks, Gran, for feeding us breakfast.” Shin thanked Yuba and lowered himself onto a cushion by the fireplace.

“Thank you for the meal, Lady Yuba.” Sayo sat down too and bowed her head. However, she seemed rather nervous as her eyes glanced around the room. That was when Rio came out of the kitchen, carrying more dishes.

“Good morning, Sayo.”

“G-G-Good morning, Sir Rio. Is there anything I may be able to help you with?” Sayo asked nervously, offering to help.

“...No, it’s fine. We just finished serving it all. All that’s left to do is eat.” Rio gave pause at how Sayo had addressed him, then put on a smile and shook his head. In the meantime, Shin was curiously watching Sayo’s peculiar behavior.

“Rio, Ruri, you two come sit down too,” Yuba ordered. Both Rio and Ruri took their seats.

Everyone settled down in a horseshoe shape around the table, with Yuba sitting at the center. Ruri and Sayo sat at her sides, while Rio and Shin sat beside them. Sayo gave a polite bow to Rio, who sat diagonally opposite her, making Shin shoot a suspicious glare between them.

“This is Rio and Shin’s first time meeting, yes? Shin, this boy is named Rio. He’s the son of an old acquaintance of mine. He’ll be staying in our house for a while. Rio, that’s Sayo’s brother, Shin.”

An indescribable mood threatened to settle in the room, but Yuba ignored it as she casually introduced Rio and Shin to each other.

“My name is Rio. It’s nice to meet you.” Rio pasted on a sociable smile and bowed at Shin, who sat directly opposite him.

“...Right. You too,” Shin replied rather bluntly, seemingly wary of him. Sayo, who sat beside him, looked like she had something to say.

“All right, Rio went through all the trouble of making this meal, so let’s eat it before it gets cold. We can talk more after,” Yuba suggested. Then, as their gazes gathered on the plates in the middle of the table...

“Hey, Gran... This stir fry has meat in it. Isn’t that a bit fancy for breakfast? Did you pocket some extra for yourself because you’re the chief? How sneaky!” Shin’s eyes immediately locked on to the pieces of meat in the vegetable stir fry.

Meat was a luxury that couldn’t be eaten in the village very often. They kept cattle, but not for consumption — the cattle in the village were valued for their labor, and were used for things like transporting goods and plowing the fields. The only occasions where they could eat cattle meat was when the work cattle were disposed of from injury or old age, or when the distribution of hunting spoils came around to each family.

“There’s no need to panic. I haven’t been sneaky — this is meat that Rio brought with him,” Yuba explained with a wry smile.

“Oh, so that’s what it is. Well, as long as I can eat meat, I don’t care. ...Hey, this is good!” No sooner had he heard the explanation, Shin was shoving the stir fry into his mouth and complimenting the taste with rounded eyes. He gulped down some rice while the flavor of the stir fry was still in his mouth.

“Mind your table manners, Shin,” Sayo warned.

“Never mind that — you try it too. It’s so good. Ooh, this miso soup is great too!” Shin didn’t seem to care at all about Sayo’s warning as he dug into the meal with vigor.

“Geez...”

Sayo pouted her lips unhappily, but the moment she tried the stir fry her eyebrows rose in shock at the taste. “It’s delicious!”

“Right?” Shin said with a smug nod.

“The miso soup is delicious too. D-Did you really make all of this yourself, Sir Rio?” Sayo asked with a hint of envy.

“Yes. I’m glad the taste is to your liking.” Rio nodded with a faint smile.

“Ahaha, they both said what I wanted to say. It’s really good, Rio.”

“Indeed, you have quite the skill. Very impressive.”

Ruri and Yuba both agreed with smiles tugging at their lips.

“Thank you very much. I made extra rice, so feel free to get seconds.”

“Whoa, seconds! Thanks, Sayo.” Shin turned to Sayo next to him and offered out his empty bowl.

“Goodness, Shin! Have a little restraint!”

“Sayo, there’s no need for me to hold back. I’m a growing child, so pile on as much as you can.”

“I-I’m sorry, Lady Yuba. My brother is... Just... Thank you for the meal.” Sayo bobbed her head at both Yuba and Rio, then started to scoop rice into Shin’s bowl from the pot next to her. Once she returned the full bowl back to her brother, she returned to eating.

Everyone ate the breakfast Rio cooked with gusto. Then, once they had finished eating and poured a round of tea for everyone...

“Now that we’re no longer distracted by the delicious meal... Shall we get to the main point? Shin,” Yuba addressed the boy.

“Hm, what is it?”

“I called you here for a reason. I’d like to have Rio try out the work that the hunters do. Could you take him to Dola’s place after this?”

“...Huh? This guy as a hunter? Are you serious?” Having completely forgotten that Yuba had called him here for something, Shin’s delightfully full and satisfied expression turned dubious at her words.

“I am. He said he wanted to help with work in the village, so I asked him what he could do. He has quite a versatile set of skills, including the ability to hunt. Dola was looking for more people to help out, no?”

“That’s... true, but... It’s a really rigorous job, you know? Does he have the stamina? He looks pretty fragile,” Shin said, looking at Rio doubtfully.

Chapter 2: Passing Days at the Village

Two months passed since Rio began living in the village, and in that time, there was now no longer a single person there who didn’t know his name, and the villagers generally viewed him favorably.

This was partially thanks to the village chief, Yuba, taking him in, and partially thanks to him bringing back huge hauls of hunting spoils on a near-daily basis. The meat supply of the village had never been greater, and Rio was actively working in areas other than hunting, too. Using the knowledge he had gained in the Royal Academy and the spirit folk village, Rio had contributed to improving the standard of life in the village by a tremendous amount.

For example, he built a bathhouse next to the village chief’s home for the villagers to use, and distributed his homemade soap to every family in the village, to the immense approval of the women. Furthermore, by giving his advice on farming techniques and tools, he greatly increased the efficiency of the farm work, which gained the strong approval of the elderly villagers.

The rate at which the village was developing was a bit fast, but Rio felt no need to refrain from sharing his knowledge and technology.

The village also suffered from sanitary issues, which had already caused people to become sick, whereas casualties from famine could be blamed on poor harvests. Ruri’s mother had passed away at a young age from such problems, and her younger brother was only four when he died from famine.

Thankfully, Rio had both the knowledge and technology to prevent such deaths.

He had only spent a short time there, but both Yuba and Ruri considered him a beloved member of their family. Yuba, of course, knew of his circumstances already, but even Ruri treated him like a dear brother.

Nevertheless, there was a reality that Rio had to face: his time here was limited, as he would someday leave the village. That was why, for their sake, he wanted to make the village they lived in as comfortable as possible.

Rio’s feelings and actions were also acknowledged by the villagers, helping him earn their trust. Recently, the women of the village had been increasingly requesting his assistance with repairing their furniture and homes, having deemed his carpentry skills worthy of praise. While there were other craftsmen in the village, they usually already had their hands full.

Today, Rio was helping a woman fix the cracks in her walls, which were letting in drafts of air. Sayo and Ruri lead him to the house in question. After Rio completed the repairs, the portly woman who requested his help spoke to him cheerfully.

“Oh, thank you — you’ve saved me. The drafts have been so cold lately... I tried to leave it to my husband, but he made it even worse, so I was at a loss. The village craftsmen kept putting me off, too.”

“The nights are starting to get cold, after all. I’m glad I could be of help to you, Mrs. Ume. Please call me again if you need any help.” Rio shook his head at Ume, showing it was no bother at all to him.

“Sure thing. That aside, you three are always glued to each other’s sides, huh? The younger men are all green with envy, seeing you walk around with two beauties of our village, Rio.” The woman grinned happily, looking at Ruri and Sayo who stood on each side of him as Rio laughed awkwardly, his smile forced.

“Oh, stop that, Mrs. Ume. Rio and I aren’t like that,” Ruri answered with practiced ease.

“Since you’re using the singular, does that mean it’s different for Sayo?” Ume asked, changing the target of her attention.

“...Eh? Ah, no, umm, that’s...” Sayo flushed red on the spot.

“Ahahaha, Sayo sure is cute,” Ume gave a hearty, booming laugh.

Similar conversations had been occurring a lot as of late, and Sayo would react in this way nearly every time. Those initiating the conversations would bring it up to her in anticipation of her reaction, clearly making fun of Sayo’s innocence.

“Geez, get used to it already, Sayo. You should at least laugh it off like Rio,” Ruri said, then giggled happily.

“Uhh... I-It’s just...” Sayo glanced at Rio, but the moment their eyes made contact, she looked down in a fluster.

“Sayo doesn’t seem to be very comfortable around men, so try not to tease her too much. I’d be grateful if you went a bit easier on me, too. I don’t really like these kinds of conversations,” Rio said in support of Sayo.

“Hmm... In Sayo’s case, it’s not that she’s uncomfortable around men, really...”

“Right...”

Ruri and Ume looked at each other with a small sigh. The two of them looked back at Rio, who tilted his head in question.

“Well, at any rate, we’re so glad to have a boy like you here in our village. I was a bit worried at first when I heard there was an outsider in Lady Yuba’s house, but I’ll be relying on you a lot more from now on!” Ume said brightly, changing the topic. She patted Rio on the shoulder.

“It’d be my pleasure to help wherever I can.” Rio nodded bashfully.

After that, Ruri and Sayo continued to lead him to other houses that had furniture that needed to be fixed. Similar exchanges occurred wherever they went, but the blush on Sayo’s cheeks was a story for another day.

Rio and the two girls were walking along together once they were on their way home.

“Really, though — Rio sure has a lot of skills. You’re clever, you can cook, you can hunt, and you’re skillful with your hands. Not to mention the spirit arts! Every village would want someone like you,” Ruri said, nodding as she spoke.

“I’m just a jack of all trades but a master of none. None of my skills can hold a candle to a true master.” Rio shook his head with a bitter smile.

“That’s not true! Sir Rio is amazing! The villagers all opened up to you instantly because you’re so friendly!” Sayo interrupted from beside them.

“Sayo’s right, you know. Having you here has really helped us out. We’re so grateful having someone who can do pretty much everything in this village.”

“Thank you very much. I’m glad I’ve been able to assist in this village,” Rio answered embarrassedly, a somewhat happy smile tugging at his lips.

Then, at that moment, Rio and the girls came across some of the young men from the village, walking on the road as well. Sayo’s older brother, Shin, was among them. When Shin and the other boys saw Rio, their faces furrowed in displeasure.

“Are you lot together again? Rio aside... Ruri, Sayo. What happened to work?” Shin asked with a frown.

“We’re helping Rio with his work. Do you have a problem with that?” Ruri replied.

“...His work? What were you doing, Sayo?” Shin looked to his sister for a reply.

“Erm... Repairing furniture and homes. The craftsmen of the village are all occupied with building new residences, so Sir Rio is helping fix the smaller things.”

“Tch, you’re even doing that now?” Shin clicked his tongue. Sayo looked at him with a sullen expression.

“If you don’t have anything to say, then we’re going to go now. I’m tired, and I want to rest. Let’s go, you two.” Ruri urged Rio and Sayo to quickly leave the others.

Shin called after them to stop. “Wait. You can do your best sucking up to everyone, but we won’t accept you!” he said, prompting the other boys around him to agree.

“That’s right!”

“Yeah!”

“...” Rio hesitated for a brief moment. He was aware of the fact that his existence was having an impact on the lives of Shin and the other boys, making him question as to how he should react. Should he say something to them directly, shrug them off, or ignore them completely?

There were people in closed-off village communities that believed in excluding outsiders from their society, and Rio didn’t think those kinds of sentiments were wrong. He knew that they could sometimes lead to stability and peace.

In other words, he felt a sense of guilt when it came to Shin. However...

“Good grief — you’re such rude brats. Rio, don’t give them any thought. You’re already a wonderful member of our village, okay?” Ruri asserted herself bluntly and took a step forward to defend Rio.

“Ruri’s right! You’re being awful, Shin. Lady Yuba approved of Sir Rio’s stay in this village, and he’s been helping out with work this entire time!” Sayo agreed with Ruri.

However, seeing the two cute girls of the village stand up for Rio only made the boys even more unhappy, and their resistance to Rio rose above all sense of reason. Shin was particularly familiar with Sayo’s personality, so he knew she wasn’t the type to defend someone so angrily and place herself in the firing line. It left him feeling greatly shaken.

“Y-You shouldn’t fawn over a weakling like him, Sayo!”

“I-I don’t fawn over him!” Sayo hesitated for a moment, then quickly denied it.

The two glared at each other darkly, a tense air flowing between them. Just as Rio was thinking the situation was taking a bad turn...

“Shin, are you misunderstanding something? Rio isn’t a weakling by any means. Despite his appearance, he’s actually quite muscular. Right?” Ruri said, suddenly clinging to Rio’s upper arm. The boys widened their eyes in blank shock.

“Hah? W-Wha— Y-You, and him... How indecent!” A beat later, Shin seemed to have clued in on something. His face turning bright red.

Sayo was also blushing. “W-Why are you aware of that, Ruri?”

“Hm? I don’t know what conclusions you’re all jumping to, but cool your heads. Not to mention how much better Rio is than Shin at hunting, too. Now, let’s go, you two.” Ruri stuck her tongue out at the boys before dragging Rio off by the arm. On Rio’s other side, Sayo hurriedly followed after them.

Shin had frozen where he stood in embarrassment, wincing slightly as Sayo shot him one last glare when she passed by.

◇◇◇

That night, in the garden of the village chief’s house illuminated by the moonlight, Rio was working hard at swinging his sword and working up a sweat that flowed down his shirtless back.

He repeatedly swung his sword, making sure the sensation was carved into his body. His breath was coming out slightly harsher than usual, and each time he swung the sword, his sweat was sent flying. Occasionally, the wind would blow the cold night’s fog through the air, wrapping Rio’s flushed body in a cooling embrace.

Chapter 6: To the Capital Once More

Several days passed since Rio and the others returned to the village.

The trades had gone well, the villagers’ pockets were filled, and everyone had smiles on their faces. Now, it was finally time for the harvest festival, where they would pray for abundant harvests in the next year.

It was still the middle of the day, yet the men had gathered in the village square to start drinking. The women that took pride in their cooking skills had prepared a feast in the meeting hall and their individual house kitchens; they used assistants to carry the dishes to the village square, and the children of the village were eating everything up with enthusiasm.

As for Rio, he had used the village chief’s kitchen to make most of his specialty recipes, and was in the middle of preparing a feast with Ruri and Sayo. He was making meat pie, apple pie, and a prototype of the kamutan he had promised Sayo.

Since no one in the village knew how to make the noodles for kamutan, and meat pie and apple pie weren’t dishes that were eaten in the Karasuki Kingdom to begin with, Rio took the lead with Ruri and Sayo’s assistance. Naturally, the kamutan noodles were all homemade, and had been prepared two days in advance. Two enormous pots had been placed over the hearth, one with shoyu soup and one with miso soup simmering inside.

“Wow — it smells great. We’ll really be able to eat kamutan...” Ruri sniffed at the aroma wafting from the pot with a blissful expression.

“I’ve only made it a few times myself, so I’m sort of an amateur. It might be a different method compared to how it’s made in the capital... The soup was made experimentally, too, so I don’t have much confidence in its taste either,” Rio said a bit worriedly.

“It’s fine! I’m sure everyone will ask for seconds. From what I taste-tested, the soup seems delicious.”

“That’s right — they’ll definitely want you to make it again. Or rather, they’ll want to make it themselves!”

Both Ruri and Sayo spoke with certainty.

“It takes quite a lot of effort and ingredients, but you’re right. I want to make it again... Although, I may never be able to make the same soup again...” Rio nodded with a happy smile. He didn’t know if he’d still be in the village this time next year, but he hoped to be able to make kamutan again as a group of three.

After letting the soup simmer for a little under an hour, they carried the pre-prepared noodles and baked pies together to the square. When the villagers found out Rio had made kamutan, they swarmed around him.

He reheated the soup on a makeshift cooking stove made from spirit arts at a corner of the square, and boiled the noodles. When the villagers tasted the completed kamutan, they all yelled “It’s delicious!” one after another.

Rio looked at all their faces and decided it had been worth all his hard work. His features crinkled happily. The meat pie and apple pie were a huge hit too.

Before long, Rio and the girls joined in on the feast, enjoying the food and drink as they watched people sing and dance cheerfully at the center of the square. It was a warm gathering that was constantly filled with laughs.

However, when evening approached...

...Hm?

Rio suddenly took the spirit stone out of his pocket. A spell formula had appeared on the surface of the stone, and it was emitting a strong light and heat.

This spirit stone was the core of the intruder detection barrier Rio had modified to cover the whole village after the Gon incident. He normally deactivated it during the day, when the villagers passed in and out so frequently, but he had turned it on just in case during the feast.

Who could it be? A traveler, a merchant, a guest... It’s coming from the east side. Rio suddenly stood up, ignoring all the partying villagers.

The spirit stone emitted a stronger light in the direction of the intruder, so he quietly walked off in that direction. On his way, he muttered the “Dissolvo” spell and retrieved his sword and sheath from the Time-Space Cache. After walking away from the village square for several minutes, he arrived at the fields that spread across the east side of the village and encountered a dozen or so men and women enshrouded in travel attire. He couldn’t detect any hostility, but they were all fully equipped and showed no signs of weaknesses. They seemed to be experienced practitioners of martial arts.

“Do you have business here?” Rio cautiously asked the unfamiliar party.

When the party spotted Rio with his sword in hand, they showed faint signs of wariness, but the middle-aged man and woman in the lead were staring at Rio with a slightly different look in their eyes.

“...My name is Saga Gouki. Pardon me, but may I ask your name? Could you perhaps be Sir Rio?” The man in the lead introduced himself as Gouki, before asking for Rio’s name.

As soon as Rio heard the Saga family name, he immediately recalled Hayate, who he had become acquainted with just recently. Perhaps this was his father, Rio thought.

“That is correct... Would you perhaps be Lord Hayate’s father?” Rio replied.

“So it is you, Sir Rio! It is an honor to be in your great presence.”

Overcome with emotion, Gouki kneeled on the spot. No, not just Gouki — the others around him also knelt before Rio at once, showing no concern for the state of their clothes at all.

“Y-Yes?” Unable to comprehend the situation, Rio was taken aback. “Erm, we haven’t met before, right...? Have you mistaken me for someone else? If you could all stand up first, I’d appreciate it...” he said after a beat.

“There is no mistake. Sir Rio, both my wife Kayoko beside me and I once graciously served your mother: Karasuki Ayame,” Gouki said, shaking his head adamantly.

“Karasuki... Ayame?” Hearing his mother’s name along with her family name made Rio freeze.

“Your surprise is most understandable, but your mother was indeed royalty in the Kingdom of Karasuki. I have come to visit you on this occasion after receiving a letter from Lady Yuba... the mother of my close friend, Zen.”

The words coming from Gouki’s mouth were facts that were overwhelmingly shocking. Regardless of whether or not he should be believed, Rio’s rational thinking had come to a complete stop.

“...For now, allow me to guide you to the village chief’s house. Then, I shall go fetch Yuba, and you can tell me your story from the beginning. Would that be all right? Please, stand up,” Rio somehow managed to say.

Even if no one was around because of the banquet, the fields weren’t the right place for this conversation, and he needed some time to calm down.

“I understand. Then, if you would please excuse our intrusion.” Gouki and the others nodded and solemnly stood to their feet.

“Please, come this way.” With a small sigh, Rio started leading them. Gouki’s party followed him in a nearly reverent manner.

After guiding them to the village chief’s house, Rio made his way to the square with haste and found Yuba talking to the other villagers. He whispered into her ear, explaining the situation. Despite her surprise, Yuba immediately understood, and smiled.

“...I see. All right — let’s go, Rio,” she gently said to him.

The two immediately made their way to the village chief’s house. They barely exchanged any words on the way, but as the house came into view, Yuba suddenly opened her mouth.

“...Rio, no matter what, you will always be my grandchild. Nothing can change that. At least, that’s what I believe. It may seem sudden, but I wanted to tell you this now.”

“Yuba... Yes, I feel the same way.” Rio had sensed that Gouki’s earlier words had more or less been the truth.

“Thank you. Shall we go inside?” Yuba asked with a somewhat happy grin, before stepping into the house.

◇◇◇

In the living room of the village chief’s house, Rio, Yuba, Gouki, and Gouki’s wife Kayoko, were facing each other. The attendants Gouki had brought along were guarding the premises in order to ensure that no one would overhear their discussions.

Gouki and Kayoko knelt, side by side. “Sir Rio, please accept our sincerest apologies for putting this unexpected shock upon you out of the blue,” they said, bowing deeply.

“No, there’s no need to apologize for that...” Rio shook his head in borderline confusion.

“Lord Gouki, may I assume that your presence here means you have obtained the appropriate permissions?” Yuba asked Gouki on Rio’s behalf.

“Indeed. We are not here of our own accord, but under the order of His Majesty.” Gouki nodded firmly.

“I see. Then, please tell him everything.”

Yuba seemed relieved — the truth could finally be revealed. It was the same feeling as if an evil had been vanquished.

“Of course — that is why we are here. Both His and Her Majesty wish to extend their gratitude and apologies to Lady Yuba for all the suffering you must have endured up until now.”

“I am honored.” Yuba lowered her head gratefully.

“Indeed,” Gouki nodded at Yuba. “...Now, Sir Rio. May I tell you the story of what happened to Princess Ayame and Zen, my close friend?” he asked Rio.

“...Yes. Please.” Rio stared at Gouki and agreed.

Then, Gouki slowly began to speak.

“The story begins 12 years ago... But first, let me tell you about the relationship between me and Zen — your father. Lady Yuba can fill you in on anything that happened before that, though...” Gouki said, looking at Yuba.

“Zen was an awkward child, but he was kind and clever nonetheless. We were at war with the neighboring Kingdom of Rokuren at the time, so every village was going through tough times. As the second son, Zen decided to leave and reduce the number of mouths to feed, and went off one day to voluntarily enlist as a soldier.” Yuba spoke of Zen from before Gouki was acquainted with him with a somewhat nostalgic smile.

“Zen had a natural talent for anything related to spirit arts and military arts. On top of that, it was the middle of a war period, as Lady Yuba said. He started as a mere soldier, but soon distinguished himself and achieved feats worthy of His Majesty’s attention. And so, His Majesty granted him the rank of a warrior. That was when I met Zen.”

It was tradition in the Karasuki Kingdom for newly-appointed warriors to face off with their predecessors. In this case, it was Gouki who had sparred with Zen. Although Gouki was much younger at the time, he was one of the leading warriors in terms of skill in the kingdom. And yet, despite Zen being self-taught, Gouki struggled to come out on top in their battle.

“It was only a sparring match, but there weren’t many opponents that could make my heart leap like Zen did. His abilities were the real deal. That was why I strongly recommended him as a bodyguard for the royal family. As you know already, that royal family member was Princess Ayame.”

“Mom... My mother was royalty...” Rio muttered, not quite processing the reality of that fact yet.

“Princess Ayame wasn’t high in succession for the throne, but she was renowned even in the neighboring kingdoms as the beauty of Karasuki,” Gouki said with a huff, a pleasant smile on his face.

“My Lord, that’s disrespectful,” Kayoko muttered in a cold voice, having maintained her silence beside Gouki the entire time.

“R-Right. Anyhow, that was how Zen became Princess Ayame’s bodyguard.” Gouki changed the subject in a hurry.

While Zen had no faults in terms of his militaristic prowess, the fact he was a mere villager had caused a few outcries.

“There were many who didn’t want to leave the protection of royalty to a commoner that was rising up in the world. Abilities aside, he lacked education and social status. That being said, Princess Ayame also had Kayoko and I as her guards, so we were able to beat all the necessary education into him. Most importantly, Princess Ayame herself had taken a liking to him...”

Zen had taken the position as Ayame’s bodyguard without any issue.

“If I may dare to say, to someone like Princess Ayame, who had a sheltered upbringing, Zen was an embodiment of the outside world. She would ask Zen everything about what life was like in his village.”

Ayame found herself drawn to Zen in no time at all. Anyone looking on could see what had happened with ease. Similarly, Zen also found himself drawn to Ayame as time went on.

That being said, Ayame was still a princess, and though Zen had been promoted to a warrior, he was still a former farmer. Because of that, the gap between their statuses was too great, and Zen chose to conceal his feelings.

“Actually, Princess Ayame secretly visited the village a number of times. Zen desperately tried to stop her, insisting that there was nothing to see in his village, but Princess Ayame refused to budge. We were all at our wits’ end.”

“So... Something like that happened...” Rio said, listening intently to the beginnings of his parents’ relationship.

In the meantime, Gouki was chuckling heartily at the memories he’d conjured up. Then, he suddenly regained his serious expression.

“That was when the Kingdom of Rokuren came forth with a peace treaty during a lull in the war.”

Peace treaties weren’t particularly rare occurrences; in fact, several had already been formed during the long warring years between the Karasuki and Rokuren kingdoms. The two kingdoms had a long history with each other; the Rokuren Kingdom had incited the war to begin with, but needlessly prolonging a war was undesirable for the kingdom’s economy and did not fare well with the citizens. This was what lead the Karasuki Kingdom to accept the peace treaty.

And so, to celebrate the treaty and to quell civilian unrest, a great festival was held in the capital of Karasuki, with the prince of Rokuren attending as an ambassador. The ceremony itself progressed peacefully, and the peace treaty was formed without issue. All that was left was for the prince of Rokuren to return home, and the temporary time of peace would begin.

However, on the night of his return, an incident occurred: someone tried to kidnap Ayame after she had retired for the night. However, Zen had been guarding Ayame from the shadows, and was able to apprehend the perpetrator before he succeeded.

It was revealed that the kidnapper was an attendant of the Rokuren prince.

Zen immediately tried to have him explain why he was putting the peace treaty that had just been established at risk, but the perpetrator used a secret weapon that had been prepared in advance to kill himself first. After that, the castle immediately burst with activity, despite it being the middle of the night. An emergency meeting was held between the leaders of Karasuki and the ambassador of Rokuren. The Karasuki Kingdom requested an explanation of the events at said meeting, but the Rokuren prince refused to comply, and instead reacted with indignation that his attendant was kidnapped and killed.

From the Karasuki Kingdom’s point of view, it was the Rokuren side that had attempted the kidnapping, the perpetrator was dead, and the bodyguard — Zen — was the only one at the scene of the crime. On top of that, Ayame herself had been asleep in her room. Still, there wasn’t enough evidence to impeach the Rokuren Kingdom.

Meanwhile, the Rokuren side was also lacking evidence, but the prince used the fact his attendant was dead as a means to stubbornly insist that their trust was betrayed. Negotiations between the two parties was inevitably soured, and there was no choice but to break the newly-formed peace treaty.

“The Kingdom of Rokuren established additional conditions: Zen’s execution, and a political marriage between the Rokuren prince and Princess Ayame. With that, they would forgive the death of the attendant, and maintain their side of the peace treaty. Even looking back on it now, it still makes my blood boil,” Gouki said, his body trembling with rage.

If everything was indeed as Gouki had said, then Rokuren’s demands were completely brazen and shameless. Rio grimaced without realizing it. He could only form his own assumptions of the political background of the time from Gouki’s words, but apparently, there had been rumors of how the sociable Rokuren prince was cruel and philandering. If someone like that were to marry Ayame in a political marriage... Well, it wasn’t a positive thought.

At any rate, while the Rokuren side’s demands sounded completely ridiculous, it was part of diplomacy to consider even the most ridiculous of requests seriously. Furthermore, the Rokuren Kingdom distorted the truth of the peace treaty being ruined and spread it throughout the streets, manipulating the emotions of the citizens and society as a whole. The citizens of the capital grew anxious, which rapidly deteriorated into discontent, and even resulted in a few protests. Even within the Karasuki royal castle, there were a significant amount of court nobles that opposed the war. The authority of the king may have been able to suppress that discontent, but it would have only been on the surface. The Karasuki Kingdom had lost the first hand, and was now cornered into a disadvantageous position.

“That being said, there was no guarantee that the Rokuren Kingdom would quiet down even if we accepted their terms. At the same time, revoking the peace treaty that had just been established and resuming the war instead would have made civilian unrest reach explosive levels, ruining the morale of the kingdom. We had to make a move to turn the tables on such a hopeless situation. That was why His Majesty pretended to agree to the demands in order to buy time. In the end, he gave the order for Zen to take Ayame and flee the kingdom.”

While it wasn’t much, they were able to buy time within the country this way. In the meantime, the king and several of his chief vassals devised a secret plan to execute.

“His Majesty selected the best of the best to form a small troop of warriors that would act in secret, and dispatched them to the Rokuren Kingdom. Then, he made an official announcement that Zen had taken Princess Ayame and fled.”

Of course, the prince of Rokuren was enraged by that. “You’ve toyed with the wrong man!” he had said as he returned to his kingdom and proudly declared war.

At the same time, the discontent within the country was directed toward Zen and Ayame for running away instead. It was simply too irresponsible of them. There was no choice but to capture them and make them take responsibility for their actions.

However, the sparks of war were already alight. The opposing parties within the Karasuki Kingdom reluctantly agreed to mobilize their armies and began their advance into the Rokuren Kingdom. In response to the Karasuki army’s movement, the great army of the Rokuren Kingdom was also mobilized. Then, the two armies met each other at the kingdom border in a stand-off.

It was at this time that the elite squad of a select few Karasuki warriors made their move, amongst which Gouki was included. They launched a surprise attack on the amassed Rokuren army troops from behind, their goal being to take the head of the senior officers.

The elite squad consisted of warriors with the greatest amount of loyalty toward the royal family. They had all amassed great ill will toward the Rokuren kingdom from the entire situation. Thus, their dauntless assault began while their troop morale was at its peak.

The warriors stormed into the heart of the enemy camp in no time at all, and dropped the heads of the enemy generals as they were in the middle of a meeting, one by one. Furthermore, they captured the Rokuren prince, who was among them. As a result, the first battle was won with only a surprise attack — it was a historically successful victory.

“The Rokuren army dispersed and fled after they lost their prince and some of their generals, which raised the morale of our troops higher than it had ever been... It was almost as though opposition toward the war had been a lie. Then, our army advanced forward before the Rokuren army could reform itself, and we secured several important bases in succession. Thus, the Kingdom of Rokuren quickly surrendered.” Gouki spoke about the situation back then with a pleasant expression.

As Rokuren was the one that surrendered, they entered the status of being a defeated kingdom. Rather than a peace treaty, Karasuki was able to set advantageous conditions for itself as the victorious kingdom. With so many of those conditions one-sidedly forced upon the other side, Karasuki prospered. The citizens’ discontent was dispersed in no time.

“However, while the result may have been an overwhelming victory, the fact was, we had crossed a dangerous bridge. The events that led up to the start of the war were filled with deception and lies, and if we warriors had made any errors, the war could have gone in their favor. More than anything, the fact that His Majesty had ordered Zen and Princess Ayame to flee was simply too damaging. The two of them were officially treated as felons for willingly running away together and causing the start of the war.”

And so, the two of them lost their place in the Yagumo region. At the same time, the social barrier between Zen and Ayame had also been removed. It was ironic.

“At the time, His Majesty was aware that Princess Ayame had fallen for Zen, and that Zen felt the same way toward Princess Ayame. However, there was no way for the two to be together if Zen remained as Princess Ayame’s bodyguard. While they may have been able to shoot down the Rokuren prince’s demands for a new plaything, she would inevitably end up in a political marriage with an undesirable partner. And so, His Majesty decided he would rather entrust her to Zen instead. As a result, His Majesty has always been plagued with apprehension over whether or not that was the correct choice...”

After the war, the king of Karasuki had sent out a wanted list to neighboring kingdoms with Zen and Ayame’s names on it. Furthermore, to completely hide the truth, he placed a gag order on the few who were in on the situation. Only Yuba was informed because of her status as Zen’s mother, but she too was forbidden to speak. That was why she was unable to tell Rio the truth.

“We have lingering regrets, too. Kayoko and I have always blamed ourselves for being unable to accompany Princess Ayame...” Gouki said with a shameful expression.

Gouki and Kayoko were already married at the time, and Kayoko was carrying Hayate in her stomach. It simply wasn’t feasible for her to endure the harsh life of being on the run while pregnant.

Furthermore, by having Gouki and Kayoko remain, the circumstances would make Zen and Ayame’s elopement seem much more authentic.

And yet, the two of them were Ayame’s bodyguards. Of course, they did not regret giving birth to Hayate, but the question of whether they should have forced themselves to go along with Ayame had always lingered in the air.

“But then, just the other day, I received a letter from Lady Yuba that informed me of Sir Rio’s presence, and that he had come from a far away land in search of clues about his parents.”

If the news had come from anyone else, Gouki might not have believed them, but the one who had relayed the information was Rio’s grandmother; her words had a much higher level of authenticity. That was why Gouki had brought Kayoko along to seek a decision from the king. He had given them the responsibility of revealing the truth if Rio was truly Ayame’s son.

“I was overcome with emotion the moment I laid my eyes upon you, Sir Rio. The traces of Princess Ayame and Zen are most pronounced in your features. That was how I was certain — there was no mistake of you being Princess Ayame’s son.”

Rio personally felt it was a little hasty of him to think that way, but perhaps it simply meant that he was that similar to Ayame. Zen, too. He couldn’t remember Zen’s face, but even when he tried to look back on his childhood, there were memories of Ayame’s face he still couldn’t quite put together.

“His Majesty the king and Her Highness the queen — in other words, Princess Ayame’s parents — wish to meet with you. Sir Rio, would you please consider traveling to the capital with me?”

“The two of them... want to meet me...”

The other party were the people who should be Rio’s grandmother and grandfather, but it honestly didn’t feel quite real — he didn’t even know their faces, after all. But, since they were Ayame’s parents, he did feel the desire to meet them himself.

And anyway, he didn’t think they would back down so easily if he rejected them now.

Rio took a deep breath to calm himself. “I understand,” he agreed in a slightly stiff voice.

A smile of relief lit up on Gouki’s face. “Thank you very much for your acceptance. I apologize profusely for the short notice, but I am hoping to depart from this village early tomorrow morning. We will guarantee your safety on the journey.”

And so, Rio headed toward the capital once more.

◇◇◇

Several days after Rio departed from the village, he visited the royal castle of the Karasuki Kingdom. By accompanying Gouki and Kayoko, he was able pass through the entrance without being questioned, and was then led to a particular room. There, an older middle-aged couple were waiting: they were the king, Karasuki Homura, and the queen, Karasuki Shizuku.

“O-Ooh, you must be Rio... Indeed, I can see traces of Ayame,” Homura said in a shaking voice as he staggered to his feet, eyes fixed on Rio’s face. Meanwhile, Shizuku was staring at Rio’s face with overwhelmed emotion.

His Majesty, King Homura, and Her Highness, Queen Shizuku... The queen really looks just like mom.

Chapter 10: A Resolute Departure

It was the long-awaited day of the harvest festival. Coincidentally, it had also been exactly one year since the day Gouki and the others appeared before Rio.

“Rio, the pie’s done baking!”

“The soup is simmering steadily here!”

“L-Lady Komomo! It’s dangerous to peek into the pot like that.”

Just like last year, Rio was cooking in the kitchen of the village chief’s house; this time, however, the members were different than last year, where it was just Ruri and Sayo. At present, there were four others apart from Rio in the kitchen: Ruri, Komomo, Aoi, and Kayoko.

While Kayoko silently worked away at cooking her specialty foods, the other members were working together to make the same kamutan and pie as last year. Ruri was used to cooking, but Komomo only started learning bit by bit when she came to live in the village, so she was still somewhat dangerous in the kitchen. In contrast, her mother Kayoko was cooking with tremendous knife skills.

Once the food was safely completed, they carried the dishes out to the square where the main venue was. The men of the village were already drinking, singing, and dancing with plenty of excitement. Among them was Gouki, who mingled with the rest of them with merriment. He seemed to be winning at a sumo-like sport with a consecutive streak.

“There are no social ranks here! Anyone with confidence in their skill may challenge me freely!” Gouki announced loudly, naked above the waist.

“Go get ’em, General Gouki!”

“Dola, it’s your turn!”

“Don’t be crazy! There’s no way I’d win!”

The men of the village raved on.

“...I can’t believe he had the nerve to leave Sir Rio and enjoy the banquet alone. I must have a word with him later,” Kayoko muttered in a cold voice as she spotted Gouki.

“No, please don’t worry about me. There are no ranks here, after all.” Rio shuddered softly as he quietly sent Gouki a lifeline.

“I understand,” Kayoko replied with a slightly disappointed look.

“All right! We’ve made kamutan again this year! Anyone who wants a serving, get in line!” Ruri yelled at the people in the square.

The villagers all gathered at once and worked together with the village ladies serving the kamutan for quite some time.

“We should join them and start eating, too, Komomo. I’m starving!”

“Yes. The kamutan Sir Rio made... I’m looking forward to it!”

Ruri and Komomo served their own helpings of kamutan.

“Thank you very much for your assistance. I apologize for making someone of your status work like this. If you’d like to, I was hoping we could eat together.”

“We have been invited to this harvest festival by the kindness of Lady Yuba — the least I could do in gratitude is assist. To receive Sir Rio’s words of gratitude, on top of having a meal together...” Kayoko said in an extremely humbled manner.

“No, this is just a simple village. There’s no need to act so formal in front of the others... Not to mention, Komomo is always eating together with us, so it’s too late for that now. Come this way,” Rio said, walking toward the area where Ruri and Komomo were sitting.

Hayate was also there — it was the area allocated for welcoming the Saga family. And so, they all sat down and began their meal as they chatted pleasantly amongst each other. Eventually, Gouki returned to join the conversation, too.

Around an hour later, Sayo hesitantly approached Rio.

“U-Umm! Sir Rio! Do you have a moment?” she asked him. The eyes of everyone present gathered on her. Sayo was trembling with a terribly nervous face.

“Yes. How may I help you, Sayo?” Rio looked up at her hovering figure and noticed she was wearing a familiar hairpin in her hair. He smiled — happily, for some reason.

“U-Umm. I wanted to talk to you...” Sayo was being very timid, but a strong will could be seen in her eyes.

“Sure. Shall we move somewhere else, then?” Rio suggested. He also wanted to talk to her before he left.

“Y-Yes. If possible, then, please.”

“I understand. Everyone — please excuse me for a moment,” Rio notified the others apologetically before rising to his feet. Then, he walked to an isolated area with Sayo.

Komomo was staring after the two of them with a slightly befuddled expression.

◇◇◇

On a roadside where the hustle and bustle of the banquet could be faintly heard, Rio and Sayo stood facing one another. Sayo was shaking in extreme nervousness.

Rio spoke first. “...You’re still using that hairpin.”

“Ah, yes.” Sayo nodded uncomfortably.

“Was it around spring when Shin asked me to stay in the village, and you and I became estranged?”

“...Yes. I’m sorry for causing you so much trouble at the time.” Sayo bowed her head apologetically.

“You weren’t any trouble — I was just worried that I said something that hurt you, or that maybe you hated me now,” Rio said, letting out a troubled and bitter laugh.

“That’s not true! It’s impossible! You didn’t do anything wrong...”

“Could I ask you one thing?” Rio asked out of the blue, making Sayo nod stiffly.

“...Yes.”

“On the day that Shin appeared before me... Did that have something to do with me telling you I was leaving the village?”

“It... did. The one who didn’t want you to leave the village was actually me. That day, when you told me you were leaving the village, I... I got really sad... And was crying when I got home. My brother went wild when he saw me... and acted on my behalf...” Sayo could feel her heart thud as she spoke. Her whole body was burning, yet she was trembling as though she was cold.

“So that’s... what it was... Sayo, I...”

Rio’s expression darkened bitterly. He felt deep regret as he tried to tell Sayo there was no change in his mind to leave the village.

“U-Umm! There was something I wanted to tell you...” Sayo said with determination.

“...Sure, what is it?” Rio asked, focusing his eyes on Sayo’s face.

“Umm, that is... I know you might find it a nuisance to hear this, but... I-I... I like you, Sir Rio!” Sayo suddenly bowed her head as she confessed to him.

“...”

The surprise confession made Rio flinch. He looked down at Sayo’s lowered head, dumbfounded, and wondered what he should say to her.

What would be the proper response? The answer to that was obvious: it was either to accept or reject her words.

But, once he reached that point in his thought process, Rio instantly had the answer of which one he should pick.

He had known from the very beginning.

“...I’m sorry. I cannot return your feelings, Sayo.” Rio clenched his hands into fists and shook his head as though to stifle the pain in his heart.

“...I-Is that because you’ll be leaving the village, Sir Rio?” Sayo’s face twisted with heartbreak, but she seemed to have been prepared for the rejection as she asked that question.

“That isn’t the sole reason, but yes,” Rio said, deciding to reply truthfully about his feelings.

“Then — please take me with you!” Sayo proposed immediately.

“...That would be impossible, Sayo.” Rio’s eyes widened at Sayo’s instant response with no sign of hesitation, but he still shook his head.

“It’ll be fine! I worked my hardest so that I wouldn’t be a hindrance! For this past year, I’ve been practicing spirit arts every single day!” Sayo insisted with desperation.

“You did such a thing...” Rio could keenly feel Sayo’s emotions, rendering him speechless in spite of himself.

Half a year ago would have been springtime; she probably started practicing soon after Shin had groveled at Rio’s feet.

All in order to...

“Please. Take me with you. I-I want to go. I’ll do anything... I’ll work my hardest to not get in your way, so, please!”

Sayo was desperate — she bowed her head in a show of that desperation.

“...I’m sorry, but that isn’t the issue. I have no intention of returning your feelings,” Rio said regretfully, averting his eyes from Sayo.

“T-That’s fine. You don’t have to look at me. You don’t have to do anything... Just... At the very, very least... Let me stay by your side. Please.”

Tears fell from Sayo’s eyes as she grabbed Rio’s hand. She was desperately trying to make an appeal for her feelings.

“Sayo... I’m sorry. I’m really sorry,” Rio apologized, face twisting with guilt. After much thought, those were the only words he was able to put together. He wasn’t tactful enough to think of anything better.

He felt ashamed — did those feelings originate from his guilt toward Sayo, his sympathy toward Sayo, or his own hatred for himself? No one could know. The only one who would know was the person himself, but not even Rio knew.

“Fweh... Uuh... G-Guh... Sniff.”

After letting go of her painful grip on Rio’s hand, Sayo was unable to hold back her tears, having a keen understanding that it was pointless.

It was Sayo’s first heartbreak, but somehow, she knew. She had seen it coming... That this love would be fruitless. She knew, because she could feel that Rio was in a very far away place.

However, for Sayo, who was in the middle of experiencing her first love, she wasn’t able to give up and completely close off any possibilities.

That was why she had to do something. Yuba had told her that Rio was firmly determined, no matter how much she tried to stop him, so she had to desperately think of another effective option other than stopping him.

That was when Sayo came to realize that if Rio would leave, even if she tried to stop him, then she should just follow him instead.

That being said, in order to do that, she had to, at the very least, not be a hindrance. However, it was clear that just dabbling in spirit arts wasn’t enough for her to satisfy that.

She also didn’t think that she could fill that gap in the half-year before Rio left the village.

Even then, Sayo desperately worked her hardest. Even if it didn’t work out, she blindly exerted herself with the hope that her devotion would be acknowledged.

And yet... it still wasn’t enough.

“...”

Rio couldn’t bear to watch Sayo breaking down in tears before him. He almost placed a hand against her shoulder without thinking, but clenched his fist tightly and stopped himself.

“Gah, what in the world...?!”

With his vision impaired by the spray, Gouki narrowed his eyes a bit. Rio used that opening to move around Gouki and cut into his side, thrusting his wooden sword right before his throat.

“That’s enough! The victor of this match is Lord Rio,” Kayoko, the referee, said without a moment’s delay.

“...I’ve lost.” Gouki let the strength drain from his body as he accepted his defeat.

“Thank you very much.” Rio withdrew his sword with a bow.

“My goodness. Creating such a large volume of water in an instant in an environment that doesn’t have moisture at all... I am in awe indeed. It seems Lord Rio has exceptional talent for spirit arts too.” Gouki praised Rio without restraint.

“F-Father! Wasn’t that last attack too much?!” Hayate’s voice called out. He had been standing alongside Aoi in shock until now, but his thoughts had finally recovered enough to object to that last slash attack.

“Lord Rio would have been able to handle it. I used that hidden skill only because I believed in him. He ended up fine, did he not?” Gouki shook his head with a wry smile, but Hayate refused to accept that.

“You are only speaking in hindsight! If that had made direct contact, he would have died!”

“Hayate. That is crude of you, you realize? There are some things that can only be understood by facing him like that. Personally, I knew that the attack would not reach him.”

“I-It is true that Lord Rio boasts an abnormal strength...”

“Lord Gouki only launched that skill because he believed I could deal with it.” Rio spoke up in support of Gouki with a strained smile.

“B-But, Lord Rio...”

“Perhaps it’d be a different matter if he had unleashed it to take me by surprise mid-battle, but it was launched from straight on as a direct challenge to me. Also, I was the one who desired a match on par with actual combat. I was more than prepared for the risks.”

“That’s...” There weren’t many humans that could handle that attack, even if they knew it was coming. It wouldn’t be strange for most people to cower in fear simply from receiving Gouki’s vigor from straight on. And to see through that slashing attack and select a means of escape on top of that... Hayate definitely wouldn’t want to try it.

But in reality, Rio didn’t seem fazed about receiving the attack, so Hayate couldn’t object any further.

“That’s how it is, Hayate. Well, I thought he would avoid it if anything...” Gouki nodded with a triumphant expression, but he muttered the latter half of his words so faintly, they were barely audible. He glanced over at Kayoko and realized he was on the receiving end of a cold gaze.

Well, perhaps I may have gotten a little too fired up, he thought to himself with a cold sweat.

No matter how close to real combat their match may have been, it still wasn’t a good idea to launch a lethal attack against an opponent that was to be respected. Kayoko would definitely give him a light scolding about it later.

“...However, that doesn’t change the fact that I used a dangerous skill. Lord Rio, please accept my apologies.” Gouki bowed his head deeply at Rio regretfully.

“No, it’s fine. I was able to witness a magnificent skill.” Rio shook his head agreeably. It was a skill that had been launched only because they both sensed each other’s abilities and believed it wouldn’t hit. If anything, Rio found it to be an honor.

“U-Umm!” Komomo’s voice suddenly interrupted them. Everyone present affixed their gazes on her.

“Please spar with me too!” Her big eyes sparkled brightly as she challenged Rio to a match.

“Erm...” The sudden request caught Rio unaware, putting him at a loss for words.

“Hahaha! Komomo tends to be drawn toward strong people. She must be unable to contain herself after seeing Lord Rio’s fight just now.” Gouki laughed heartily as he commented on Komomo’s personality.

“Yes! That fight just now was wonderful! I’ve never seen anyone defeat my father before!” Komomo agreed with an innocent smile.

“So, please!” She said, bowing her head enthusiastically.

“...Understood. That’s fine with me,” Rio agreed with a smile, impressed with Komomo’s earnest attitude.

“Lord Rio, thank you for agreeing to my daughter’s request. ...Komomo. Lord Rio is a person far above yourself. Consider it an honor to be able to practice with one of such higher skill.”

“Yes! Thank you very much!”

Komomo nodded energetically, thanking Rio.

“Then, first, allow me to clean up the water scattered everywhere.”

Rio pulled all of the nearby water formed in puddles on the ground toward him, swirling it into a spiral. Then, he lightly moved his hand, and drove it away into a corner of the training grounds. It was over in mere seconds, but everyone other than Rio watched the sight unfold with wide eyes.

“Producing such an amount of water instantly... Lord Rio must be quite an incredible practitioner of water spirit arts. I have never seen any water spirit arts this splendid in my many years of life,” Gouki said in surprise.

“I wouldn’t go that far...” Rio shook his head, glossing over the topic. Based on the reactions of Gouki and the others, he figured his actions were of a slightly advanced grade.

For the record, this level of spirit arts would have been a piece of cake for the high elf Orphia, and the other water spirit art users in the village would have been able to use it easily as well. But since the spirit folk had a much higher aptitude for spirit arts compared to humans, it was difficult to make a comparison to Rio.

“Now, Miss Komomo. Shall we?” Rio headed to the center of the training grounds promptly, before he could be hounded with any troublesome questions.

“Yes!” Komomo was rearing to face Rio, following after him in excitement.

With that, everyone else’s attention was drawn to the match about to start. Komomo stood in the center of the training grounds with a gallant expression. She took a deep breath to calm herself, before bracing her wooden sword in both her hands, aimed right at eye level. Rio’s eyes widened in awe at how Komomo’s aura changed completely.

The sparring match started soon after that. While there was a clear gap in their skills, the match developed in the form of Rio helping Komomo practice her skills.

“That was a bad move. You should have widened the distance between us and regained your footing first.” Rio allowed Komomo to attack him, but whenever parts of her movements were poor, he took advantage of it aggressively and struck her where it hurt.

There were multiple times where the match would have been decided under normal circumstances, but the sparring match continued until Komomo was satisfied with how much she had swung her sword. Thus, Komomo began to move while thinking about where she had gone wrong.

“Hah, hah...”

After they had exchanged enough blows, they sat on the ground and panted for breath. Komomo’s expression was extremely pleased; she had been able to gain experience she would never have been able to get normally when fighting her family, so she was filled with happiness from the bottom of her heart. The radiant sight of Rio made her feel as though she could reach higher and become stronger. Komomo could only look up at his face in fascination.

◇◇◇

The next day after the match with Gouki, Rio returned to the royal castle of the Karasuki Kingdom once again to secretly meet with Homura and Shizuku.

“I’ve heard the news... So, you’ve bested Gouki, it seems. ‘Splendid’ is all I can say.”

The first thing Homura said upon opening his mouth was high praise for Rio. He had heard of the result of the sparring match from Gouki before the secret meeting, but he had never imagined that Gouki, as someone famously known as the Fierce God, would lose. Homura had thought it was some kind of joke at first, but he knew that Gouki wasn’t the type of person to make jokes like that.

It definitely took him a while to accept the truth, but Homura had managed to regain most of his composure in the time before the meeting.

Meanwhile, Shizuku praised Rio with a dazzling smile. “You’re amazing, Rio. You even defeated Gouki!”

Unlike Homura, whose commendation was mixed with bewilderment, Shizuku was genuinely happy for Rio’s victory.

“Thank you very much.” Rio bowed his head bashfully.

“I was thinking of having you train under Gouki for a while, but it seems my concern was uncalled for...” Homura said with a trace of sadness in his smile.

He had intended to make Rio train under Gouki, after all. That way, it would have been inevitable for Rio to live in the capital and increase the frequency of their secret meetings... or so he had quietly hoped. Although he knew they had to refrain from excessive contact with Rio because of the various circumstances preventing them from revealing Rio’s identity, his desire to see Rio more was strong.

Then, whether he knew Homura’s sentiments or not, Rio spoke.

“No, I was able to gain valuable experience. There aren’t many opportunities to fight with someone like Lord Gouki. Thank you for your consideration.” Rio offered Homura words of honest gratitude.

“Is that so. Then, that is most important... But, Rio. Just sometimes is enough. Until you depart from this land, would you come to this castle again and talk with us from time to time?” Homura asked. Shizuku watched Rio in anticipation of his answer.

“That is... Of course. If that is all right with you.” On the receiving end of his grandparents warm gazes, Rio nodded timidly.

“...I see. Thank you.” Homura said gratefully and bowed his head at Rio.

“Please, there is no need to lower your head.” Rio tried to stop him in a fluster.

“No... You are wasting your precious time going along with our selfish requests. We have caused nothing but trouble and hardship for you. When I think of it that way, it makes me feel most ashamed...”

“That’s not the case. If I didn’t want to meet the two of you, I would have rejected your proposal to come here from the beginning. I have come here of my own free will,” Rio said bluntly in response to Homura’s pained words.

Whether it was Yuba, Homura, or Shizuku, there was no doubt that they were all important people to Zen and Ayame. That was why Rio wanted to get along with them, too. He wanted to hear stories of his parents that he didn’t know.

“Rio...” Shizuku muttered Rio’s name with great emotion.

“Then, we must develop this relationship more...” Homura beamed.

After that, Rio and his grandparents chatted about many things. The conversation topics focused around what they had in common: namely, charming stories of Zen and Ayame. Episodes concerning them seemed to be the most suitable compromise between the two parties.

While the three of them continued their pleasant talk to their heart’s content, their time together was limited. Homura and Shizuku had duties to attend to on this day as well, and Rio had to return to the village tomorrow. Although they made a promise to meet again at a later date, all that had been decided was that Gouki would visit the village when the time was right, with no definitive date decided. Therefore, they didn’t know when they would meet again, so they had to say anything they wanted to say here and now.

“There isn’t much time left, but is there anything else you wanted to hear?” Homura asked Rio.

“...I have a cousin in the village I’m living in right now. Would I be permitted to reveal my heritage to that girl?”

Of course, the cousin he was referring to was Ruri. As Rio considered Ruri another precious member of his family, he didn’t want to let her be the only one left out of the loop.

“Hmm. If she can strictly adhere to confidentiality, then it wouldn’t be a problem. I shall trust your judgment in this.” Homura faintly made a show of consideration before readily allowing it. That was how much he trusted Rio.

“Thank you very much,” Rio said with a grin.

And so, Rio was on the receiving end of Ruri’s barrage of questions for some time.

◇◇◇

A few days passed since Rio explained his background to Ruri.

With the fall harvest festival having come to an end, the village was entering its farming off-season before winter. At present, the villagers were preparing for staying in during the winter, as well as starting some farming work in preparation for next year.

However, for a hunter, this was the busiest season of the year.

Rio normally helped out in the fields during the afternoon, but ever since he returned to the village, he spent every day hunting until dark, catching prey to be processed into preserved food. Naturally, the amount of contact he had with the non-hunter villagers decreased, and he had pretty much only seen Yuba and Ruri as of late.

“Hey, Rio. Have you seen Sayo since you returned to the village?”

One morning, as Rio was preparing to go hunt in the hunters shed, Shin approached him.

“No. I’ve been busy with hunting, so I haven’t seen her...”

“Sayo’s been asking after you lately. Does he seem busy with his hunting duties, does he look like he’s doing well... It’s annoying, so go see her at least once,” Shin said in a slightly blunt manner.

“I apologize — it seems I have caused her to worry. I wanted to greet the others properly, too, so I’ll make some time either today or tomorrow to go see her,” Rio replied with an apologetic look of understanding.

“...Make sure that you do.” Shin’s face darkened with a conflicted expression, and he nodded curtly.

◇◇◇

The next afternoon, Rio received permission from Dola to wrap up his hunting in the morning and head down the mountain. He made an effort to show up where more people were likely to be gathered and briefly greeted everyone. After stopping at a few work areas, his final stop was a workshop where the village girls were gathered.

“Huh, Rio? What’s up?” Ruri noticed Rio’s presence first and came running over.

“Hey, Ruri. I figured I hadn’t greeted anyone since coming back to the village, so I wanted to show my face to the people I hadn’t seen yet.”

“I see. True, everyone was worried ‘cause you were gone... Wait, huh? What’s with the faces, everyone?”

Rio and Ruri had been casually holding their conversation as every girl present watched on with dumbfounded expressions. Once Ruri noticed that, she faltered.

“Tone!” The girls answered in unison.

“Tone?” Ruri cocked her head as Rio smiled wryly in realization of something.

“Your tone to Sir Rio! Why are you speaking to him so casually, Ruri?!” One of the girls pointed out, finally making Ruri understand the situation.

“Huh? Ah, that’s because...”

“What does this mean, Ruri?” Naturally, the girls all closed in on Ruri unanimously.

“No, umm...” Ruri’s gaze wandered, settling on Rio beside her for help. However, Rio took a nonchalant step back, adamantly taking on the role of an innocent bystander.

R-Rio!! Ruri stared at him with reproachful eyes.

You’re the one being interrogated, Ruri. If I stepped forward now, things would only get more complicated.

That may be true...! But still!

And so on. They exchanged conversation through their gazes, but to the girls, that only made everything seem all the more suspicious, and their silent pressure continued to grow stronger by the minute.

A cold sweat ran down Ruri’s back at the keen gazes of the girls focused on her.

“W-We’re living in the same house, so I asked him to stop talking to me in that stiff way all the time because it got tiring. It’s no big deal, really.” Ruri dodged the question with an adequate answer. She couldn’t tell them the real reason: that they were cousins.

“............” The girls all looked at each other. It wasn’t a reason they couldn’t believe, but there was something still suspicious about it — the woman’s intuition they held was telling them that.

“Ruri... told me quite some time ago to change my manner of speech, but is it so odd after all? I am afraid I am still not quite used to it...” Rio asked the girls worriedly at just the right moment.

“No, it’s not odd...”

The girls weren’t able to persistently hound Rio like they did with Ruri, so they shook their heads reluctantly. Because they stopped pursuing the topic for the moment, Ruri let out a sigh of relief.

Hmph, he doesn’t even know how I feel...

Seeing the corner of Rio’s lips curl up in amusement made Ruri pout, but Rio just started to speak to the girls with feigned ignorance. He apologized for worrying them when he left the village so suddenly, and so on.

“I’ve worried you too, Sayo. I heard from Shin.”

“F-From my brother? U-Umm, did he say anything strange?”

“No, not particularly...”

“Is that so... Then, that’s fine. So, umm, with Ruri...” Sayo seemed relieved, then muttered the start of a question.

“Yes, what is it?”

“I-It’s nothing...” When Rio tilted his head, she timidly withdrew her words.

“If possible, I’d like to greet the people of the village... But there’s so many of them. Who would be best to start with?” Komomo said, looking around.

Many of the villagers remained indoors during the winter — no one went outside without a good reason to — but there were quite a few villagers around at the moment. The villagers were starving for entertainment, so they had probably gathered to have a look when they heard an upper-class figure was visiting the village. All the village’s attention was focused on the sweet sight of Komomo walking beside Rio with a smile, dressed in her favorite hakama.

“Shall we start with the other girls first?” Rio suggested, and they approached where the village girls were gathered.

“Hello everyone.”

“H-Hello, Sir Rio.” The girls returned Rio’s greeting rather nervously.

“I’d like to introduce this girl, who will be staying in our village for a while. Does everyone have a moment?”

“Y-Yes! That’s fine!”

“This is Saga Komomo, the little sister of Lord Hayate, who previously visited the village as a tax officer.” Rio introduced Komomo so that the surrounding villagers would be able to hear too.

“My name is Saga Komomo. I will be living in this village from today on. I’m very happy to meet you all — please treat me well!” Komomo put on an adorable smile and energetically introduced herself.

“S-Sir Hayate’s little sister? So she’s a lady... So cute...” When the girls laid their eyes on a real upper-class lady, they couldn’t help but gaze at Komomo in admiration.

“Oh my, thank you so much... But everyone here is beautiful, too,” Komomo said shyly.

The sight of her won over the hearts of all the village girls.

“U-Umm! How did you come to live in our village? May I ask what your relationship is with Sir Rio...?” One girl mustered the courage to ask.

“Sir Rio is my savior. He previously saved me when I was about to be kidnapped by some scoundrels in the capital,” Komomo replied, and Rio supplemented her answer.

“It was during the trip to the capital for village trade. Perhaps you remember it, Sayo? During that shopping trip...”

“Hweh... Ah! The girl from back then?” Sayo, who had been singled out by name, widened her eyes when she remembered what happened.

“Huh? What, what? What happened?! Tell us, Sayo!”

“Eeh? Umm...” Girls brimming with curiosity closed in on Sayo.

“Typical Rio. Constantly on his guard...”

“But like, isn’t this a chance for him to marry rich?”

“No way... Ruri already has the lead on us. We’ll never have a chance now.”

The other girls all whispered to each other, while the surrounding villagers also picked up on the situation and began to discuss it in amusement. Thus, the scene instantly grew noisier.

“What is everyone in an uproar about?” Komomo asked Rio beside her and cocked her head curiously.

“Haha... I wonder what indeed.” Rio’s dry laugh was drowned out by the noise.

“Ooh, L-Lord Rio. Whatever is the matter with all this fuss?” Hayate appeared along with Ruri and Komomo’s attendant, Aoi.

Rio’s heritage had already been revealed to Hayate, who hesitated briefly before addressing him as “Lord” in front of everyone. He widened his eyes at the sight of the villagers as they noisily chatted away.

“No, I was just introducing Komomo to the villagers...” Rio explained.

“Ahaha, it doesn’t seem like this fuss will die down any time soon,” Ruri laughed in amusement.

That night, a small welcome party was held in the village chief’s house for Komomo and the others.

◇◇◇

The second day of Komomo’s stay in the village...

Hayate, who had originally come along with Komomo as an escort, had already departed for the capital in the morning. Afterward, Komomo walked around the village with Aoi.

Whenever they passed any villagers, she would enthusiastically greet them and engage them in a short conversation. At first, Komomo would be treated reverently because of the difference in her social status, but thanks to her cute appearance and friendly demeanor, the villagers soon opened up to her.

“I’m back!” Komomo greeted energetically as she returned to the village chief’s house with Aoi.

“Ah. Welcome back, Komomo.” Ruri, who had been sitting in the living room, stood up to meet Komomo.

“I’m back, Ruri. Is Sir Rio not here right now...?” Komomo asked, glancing around the room.

It seemed as though the two of them had become closer with each other since the night before.

“Rio went out to the village farms with Granny. Something about building a water wheel and waterway before the spring.”

“Waterway aside, what’s a... water wheel? Aoi, do you know?” Komomo asked.

“I do not. I have never heard of it, either.” Aoi shook her head regretfully.

“Apparently, a water wheel can automatically draw water and supply it to the fields,” Ruri explained, drawing on what she had heard.

Komomo nodded in awe. “Something that convenient... Sir Rio sure has extensive knowledge.”

“U-Umm. Excuse me!”

The voice of a visitor sounded from the entrance — it was Sayo’s voice.

“Huh, Sayo? Welcome... What’s wrong?”

“N-Nothing. I was nearby in the area, so... Are you busy?” Sayo spoke timidly as she looked around the room. When her blank expression met Komomo’s eyes, she faltered faintly, captivated by her cute face.

“You’re the one... that saved me along with Sir Rio, right?” Komomo asked with a tilt of her head.

“Huh? N-No. I just happened to be there...” Sayo denied in a fluster of hand gestures.

“You’ll get cold over there — come inside for now. Rio’s out with Granny right now, but I’ll pour you some tea,” Ruri said, inviting her inside.

“...Okay. Excuse me.” Sayo timidly stepped up to the living room.

“Hello again. My name is Saga Komomo. My attendant behind me is named Aoi. We’ll be staying in this village for a while, so we’ll be in your care.” They bowed to each other, before Komomo politely greeted Sayo. Aoi also bowed from behind her.

“I-I’m Sayo. It’s nice to meet you, Lady Komomo.” Sayo lowered her head with a nervous expression.

“There’s no need to be so formal... Please treat me like Ruri does,” Komomo looked troubled at being treated as though Sayo was afraid.

“I-I couldn’t possibly do that.”

“Ahaha, that’s just how Sayo is. Well, she’ll get used to it eventually,” Ruri said with a laugh.

“Aww, that’s a shame. By the way, how old is Sayo?”

“Umm, I’ll be fourteen in the new year. One year younger than Sir Rio.”

“Then, that would make you three years older than me. I hope we can get along.”

And so forth — the girls continued to chat amicably.

Then, after almost an hour of talking later, Yuba and Rio returned. “We’re back.”

“I’m home.”

“Welcome home!” Komomo adjusted her position to face them and got up to welcome them back with a smile.

“Thank you for welcoming us back, Komomo. I see that Sayo is here, too.” When he caught sight of Sayo sitting in the living room, his eyes widened slightly, and he lightly greeted her with a smile.

“Oh? Is Sayo here, too?”

“I-I’m intruding for a bit. Sir Rio, Lady Yuba.” Sayo timidly bowed to the two.

“Make yourself at home,” Yuba smiled brightly, welcoming her.

“Sir Rio, would you please assist me with training later?”

“Sure. We could even go right now, if you want?”

“Yes! Yes, please! Let’s get ready, Aoi.”

“Yes, Lady Komomo.”

Komomo nodded with pure delight, and returned to her room with Aoi. Rio’s lips turned up in a smile at the two of them, before going to his own room to get ready.

“It’s gotten much more lively with Komomo here. Rio isn’t bored, either, so it’s great,” Ruri said happily.

“...Yeah. That’s right. Sir Rio looks like he’s having fun,” Sayo agreed, her expression darkening with slight sadness.

◇◇◇

Thus, their busy time together passed in the blink of an eye — before they knew it, Komomo had been in the village for a whole month. The new year had just started, and early into the year, the Saga family — Gouki, Kayoko, and Hayate — visited the village in secret.

Facing each other in the living room of the village chief’s house, Gouki greeted Rio on behalf of his family. “Sir Rio, we wish you a very happy new year.”

“Happy new year. I’m honored to have you visit during such a cold time.”

“This is nothing. The changing seasons will not impede our path to you, Sir Rio. We would swim through an icy lake to reach you, if need be.”

“...I’d appreciate it if you didn’t push yourselves too hard,” Rio said with a wry smile.

“Ahaha. Rio, you really are royalty,” Ruri laughed with exasperation.

At present, the only ones in the house were those who knew of Rio’s circumstances, with Gouki and the others acting like Rio’s retainers. It made Rio seem like an untouchable existence. Even the normally sociable Komomo was respectfully quiet today, remaining behind Gouki and Kayoko.

“My mother was royalty, but I am not. I don’t actually want you to be that formal toward me...” Rio said in a disconcerted manner, looking at Gouki and the others.

“From our point of view, you are no doubt someone to be respected. Naturally, we cannot so bluntly disregard your will, but we will exert our utmost effort to moderate ourselves...”

“...I am aware of that. However, please treat me normally in front of the villagers.”

“Of course,” Gouki nodded deeply.

“...Incidentally, Komomo hasn’t been causing you any trouble, has she, Sir Rio?”

“No, she’s been a very good child. Miss Aoi has been accompanying me for her training practices, too. She has been a great help.”

“That is... good to hear. Thank you very much for agreeing to our selfish demands. We have caused much trouble for Lady Yuba and Lady Ruri, too.”

“No, we’re grateful to receive the support you have provided the village as compensation. While our village may have nothing, I hope you can leisurely enjoy your stay here,” Yuba said graciously.

“I’m really happy to be friends with Komomo, too.” Ruri shook her head with a smile.

Gouki bowed his head to Yuba and Ruri. “We are most grateful. For now, we plan on staying for about three days.”

“In that case, I’d like to give my new years greeting to His Majesty Homura and Her Majesty Shizuku, so if it isn’t too much trouble, could I accompany you on your way back?” Rio proposed.

“O-Ooh! Is that so? We were actually hoping to ask you to head on over for a visit, Sir Rio, if I may so humbly say. His and Her Majesty would surely be delighted.” Gouki smiled broadly.

He had actually been indirectly asked in advance by Homura and Shizuku, who had wanted to see Rio, so Rio’s proposal was quite the timely offer.

After that, they pleasantly chatted for a while, and the Saga family’s life in the village began. There were already rumors spreading among the villagers of the visitors, but because of Komomo, there wasn’t as much of a commotion as last time when they heard it was the Saga family.

During their stay, Gouki took Hayate and Komomo out to go hunting, sparred with them two-against-one, and fully enjoyed many outdoor activities. Three days passed in no time.

On the morning of their return to the capital, eight people of various ages and genders were gathered before the village chief’s house. Rio stood with the Saga family members being sent off, while Yuba and Ruri stood on the side doing the seeing off.

“Lady Yuba, thank you for your hospitality. It has been a long time since I’ve enjoyed myself so fully,” Gouki said, thanking Yuba with a bright smile on his face.

“I’m glad to hear that you had fun. Thanks to your assistance, our stocks of preserved food have greatly increased.” Yuba shook her head with upturned lips.

Beside her, Ruri was saying goodbye to Rio and Komomo.

“Rio, make sure you protect Komomo. Komomo, be careful on your way home.”

“Got it. I’ll be back soon.” Rio nodded calmly.

“I’ll be fine! I’ll protect Sir Rio too!” Komomo agreed enthusiastically.

“Lady Ruri, please rest assured: my father and I will guarantee Sir Rio’s safety,” Hayate said to Ruri, having been listening from nearby.

“Geez. Rio’s strong enough not to need protection, so make sure you protect Komomo instead, Sir Hayate,” Ruri replied with an exasperated face.

“I-Indeed. However...”

“Ruri’s right. She’s your precious sister, so please protect her instead of me.”

Being told to prioritize Komomo by both the person that occupied his thoughts and the person he ought to protect, Hayate was at a loss.

“Hmph, I’ll be the one to protect Sir Rio, then,” Komomo pouted, sulking.

◇◇◇

Once Rio and the others left for the capital, the village fell silent.

“It became so much quieter all at once. I hope Rio and Komomo come back soon,” Ruri murmured as she sipped at her tea in the living room of the village chief’s house.

There was practically no work to be done in the morning during winter, and with many of the villagers still asleep, Ruri had mostly been hanging out with Komomo and Rio. Now that the two of them were gone, loneliness welled up within her.

“If you’re like this now, what are you going to do when Rio really leaves the village? Lady Komomo will return to the capital when Rio leaves the village, too,” Yuba said with a wry smile.

“That’s right... Aah, it’s so lonely,” Ruri grumbled with a sigh.

“Why don’t you go talk to the village girls? You’ve only been with Rio and Lady Komomo lately, so you haven’t seen them much, right?”

“Well, everyone’s been holing themselves up indoors too, but I guess so. I haven’t spoken to Sayo lately, either... All right, I’ll be back later!” Now that that was decided, she went to visit Sayo’s house.

“Sayo, you here?” Ruri dropped by Shin and Sayo’s house, knocking on the front door as she called Sayo’s name. A slight commotion could be heard inside the house.

“R-Ruri? What’s wrong?” The door opened quietly but swiftly, revealing Sayo.

“Y-Yeah. I was wondering if you wanted to have tea together. Are you busy right now?”

“Nope. I’m free right now, so it’s fine.”

“Then, could I come in for a while? I haven’t spoken to you lately, after all.”

“Yeah... That’s fine, but... Umm, is Sir Rio out right now?” Sayo looked around as she timidly asked for Rio’s whereabouts.

“Aah, yeah. He’s gone to the capital with the rest of Komomo’s family,” Ruri said with a sigh.

“Is that so...” The tone of Sayo’s voice fell dejectedly.

“Sayo?” Ruri tilted her head curiously.

“Ah, erm, come in! Just be warned: my brother’s lazing about after eating, so it’s a little messy. I’ll get the tea ready right away.” Sayo invited Ruri inside and hurried into the house.

“Well, if it ain’t Ruri.” Shin was lounging about in the living room.

“What do you mean by that? Some greeting.”

“Nothing. You just haven’t shown your face around here for a while. What happened to Rio?”

“Rio’s gone to the capital with the Saga family.”

“Oh. I see... So that’s how it is.” Shin nodded in understanding, then glanced at Sayo as she prepared the tea, diligently extracting the tea flavor with boiled water.

“You should help Sayo out more, since it’s just the two of you living here. You’re making her do all the chores, aren’t you?” Ruri said tiredly, making Shin frown unhappily.

“...Shut up. Are you my mother?”

“That would be Sayo, not me.”

And so on. Ruri went back and forth with Shin until Sayo came over and poured tea for the two of them.

“The tea’s ready. Here you go.”

“Sayo really is a good girl, unlike you,” Ruri muttered earnestly.

“And you, too,” Shin replied sarcastically.

Ruri laughed. “I know that already, sheesh. Aah, it’s been a while since we did this. It’s so calming.”

“Hm.” Shin snorted in dissatisfaction.

“Thanks, Sayo. And while I’m at it, you too, Shin,” Ruri said gratefully.

“What’s with you all of a sudden?” Shin stared fixedly at Ruri with suspicion.

“No, it’s just that I suddenly got lonely with Rio and Komomo gone. There’s a lot less opportunity to see everyone during the winter, so I just really wanted to see Sayo,” Ruri explained.

“There are times like that, yeah. I understand how you feel...” Sayo whispered her agreement.

“Right? That’s why I was starving to see you. There!” Ruri said, suddenly hugging Sayo, who sat beside her.

“Ahaha. It’d be nice if Sir Rio came back soon,” Sayo said, smiling embarrassedly.

“Yeah. You’re right. But he said this time it might take a little longer than usual.” Ruri pouted unhappily.

“...How long until he comes back?”

“He said it might take a month.”

“A-A month... That long...” Sayo’s expression darkened.

“Apparently there’s a lot of stuff that needs to be sorted out over there,” Ruri mumbled.

“I-I wonder what Sir Rio is doing over there,” Sayo questioned in a slightly high-pitched voice. She waited for Ruri’s answer nervously.

“Hmm... Apparently someone connected to the Saga family once knew Rio’s parents or something.”

Ruri blurred the facts with a troubled expression. After all, she couldn’t reveal the truth.

“What? Rio was actually born somewhere nearby?”

“Eh, I don’t know about that. Rio said he’s been traveling for years now.”

Shin’s sharp observation made a cold sweat run down Ruri’s back.

There were no words that he could offer Sayo right now. Even if he spoke gently to her, he wouldn’t be able to do anything more than that. Since he couldn’t return her feelings, he would only be hurting her more with his half-hearted kindness.

With that thought, Rio turned on his heel, silently, his expression twisting in pain. But he slowed for a moment as he departed, fixing his gaze on the shade of a tree a slight distance away.

Then, the presence he felt from the shadows wavered faintly.

...Forgive me, Shin.

Rio whispered an apology in his heart, then distanced himself from Sayo with resolute steps.

“S-Sir Rio, wait...”

“...” He said nothing to Sayo’s weakly-spoken voice.

The distance between Rio and Sayo was close, yet hopelessly far. With no other option, Sayo could only continue to cry.

◇◇◇

Meanwhile, Shin was glaring at Rio’s departing figure from behind the trees.

That jerk knew I was here. He really is an awful guy. He clicked his tongue and frowned.

Although he wanted to follow his impulse to run after Rio and beat him up, he knew nothing would come of it.

After all, it wasn’t Rio’s fault.

Shin gave an aggravated sigh and looked at Sayo instead. She was still crouched over the ground, crying. While there were barely any people around during the festival, that didn’t mean there was no one at all.

“Damn it!” Shin scratched at his head roughly and briskly walked off. There was no hesitation in his steps as he made a beeline for where Sayo was crouched.

“Oi, Sayo.”

When Shin called out to her, Sayo’s dainty body flinched.

“Bro...ther?” Sayo looked up at Shin with the face of an abandoned puppy as she cried.

“Are you giving up? You’re satisfied now, right?” Shin suddenly asked in a voice laced with irritation.

“I-I’ll give up. B-Because... I was rejected... It’s no use anymore,” Sayo mumbled with her head hung low.

“Oh, really. You’re giving up. Well, I don’t care either way. Who would want to give their precious little sister away to a good-for-nothing like him, right?” Shin said offhandedly, which made Sayo look up at him with sullen eyes.

“D-Don’t speak badly about Sir Rio.”

“Hey, hey — are you sticking up for trash like him? I have no idea what he was so burdened with, but he always had such a depressing face.”

“...Stop it, otherwise I’ll get mad, Shin.” The normally docile Sayo’s voice was filled with rarely-seen anger.

“Sure, the girls may find his face somewhat nice to look at. He can handle household chores and handiwork without a problem, and he’s strong enough to beat the crap out of Gon and those other bastards. ...Wait, shit, saying it out loud is making me even more annoyed. But that’s just how unpleasant that guy is. A sly and shrewd jerk!” Shin ranted on and on about Rio with negativity.

“Shin! How can you say such horrible things?!” Sayo flared up.

“Hah? I could say the same for you! How could you stick up for a guy like that?! Shouldn’t you hate him? He’s the guy who rejected you. Haven’t you given up already?” Shin asked provokingly.

“I-I don’t hate him. It’s not his fault!”

“Huh? Are you stupid? Do you love him, then?” Shin questioned further with a dubious look.

“...There’s no way I could hate him.”

“I’m asking if you love him. Are you dumb?” Shin finally looked down on Sayo in exasperation, making Sayo get worked up.

“That’s right! I’m dumb! I love him!” she cried out.

“DON’T GIVE UP, THEN!” Shin yelled back without a moment’s delay.

“...?!” Sayo, in spite of herself, could not find the words for a rebuttal.

“You love him, don’t you?! So why are you giving up after being rejected just once, after you worked so hard on practicing your spirit arts every day for half a year?! You gotta be kidding me!”

“Because he’s leaving the village! I don’t know what to do!!”

“You either wait for him to return, or you follow him!”

“W-Wait for him... But I don’t know when he will return! What if he comes back and then leaves again?”

“Then follow him!”

“D-Don’t be absurd! I don’t even know where he’s going!”

Shin had an illogical counterargument for every remark, making Sayo unable to hold herself back from arguing.

“Shit, that’s right. Then you’ll just have to wait. You’d better be prepared to wait as many years as it takes, until you’ve become an old lady.”

“...If I became an old lady, he wouldn’t even look at me anymore,” Sayo muttered offhandedly.

“Good grief... You two over there. Your voices are rather loud.” Gouki appeared out of nowhere and spoke in a tired voice.

“?!” The thought of their conversation being overheard by other people made Sayo glance around with a bright red flush on her cheeks.

“Don’t worry — there’s no one around other than me. Although that may not have been the case if you continued to argue like that,” Gouki said with a wry smile, reassuring Sayo.

“You’re Sir Hayate’s father...”

“Indeed. I am Saga Gouki.”

“Were you... eavesdropping? That’s not very nice of you.” Shin glared at him unhappily.

“S-Shin! Don’t be rude!” Sayo reprimanded him in a panic.

“You’ve got guts, boy. Interesting. I wasn’t intentionally eavesdropping — you two were simply having your sibling fight at a volume I couldn’t help but hear. So I decided to step forward.” Gouki laughed with a snort.

“...And? What do you want? If you’re just here to laugh, then I’ll have to ask you to leave.”

“I’d like to speak with that girl over there. You may leave first.”

“As if I’d leave my precious sister behind.” Shin stood before Gouki with a sullen expression.

“Hm. Then, listen quietly. Are you in love with Lord Rio, girl?”

“Eh... Y-Yes,” Sayo replied with a timid nod.

“Enough to abandon the village of your birth?” Gouki fired a follow-up question immediately after she had responded.

“T-That’s...” Sayo stumbled over her reply for a moment.

“Forget it, then. It looks like I was mistaken.” Gouki turned to leave.

“W-Wait, please! I-I love him! I love Sir Rio!” Sayo grabbed Gouki’s sleeve in a panic, speaking out as though she were making an appeal for her feelings.

“...And those words are the truth?” A serious expression showed on Gouki’s face as he questioned Sayo’s resolve.

“Y-Yes!”

As the sun gradually started to set, Sayo’s voice echoed along the roadside of the village.

◇◇◇

Several days later, the day for Rio to leave the village had finally come.

A huge crowd of people were gathered near the west gate of the village to see him off. Among them were members of the Saga family, too; while Homura and Shizuku had already said their farewells before the harvest festival, he greeted them all in order, and said his farewells to the Saga family as well.

“Sir Rio, I hope that you won’t forget about me!” Komomo said, looking up with an uneasy face.

“Of course. I hope that you won’t forget about me either, Komomo.”

“Definitely! There’s no way I would ever!” Komomo nodded with a fist pump.

“Thank you, Komomo. ...Lord Gouki, Lady Kayoko, Lord Hayate. Please take care of yourselves. I’ll be looking forward to the next time we meet.” He looked at Komomo’s family members, who stood behind her, as he spoke.

“Those should be our words. Until the next time we meet, I shall sharpen my skills in anticipation, so thank you for everything.”

“Our whole family is much indebted to you. I look forward to the day we meet again.”

“To be honest, I keep being caught by surprise by... Lord... Rio. I believe we will meet again some day, so please take care of yourself on your journey.”

Gouki, Kayoko, and Hayate all offered their farewells.

“I will work diligently not to lose to you next time we meet. I wish you all the best.” Rio nodded with a cheerful nod.

“Go on, Sayo, you too. Don’t hold back!”

“Wawawah, Ruri!” Ruri pushed Sayo before Rio.

“Hello, Sayo,” Rio said with a faintly stiff smile. He hadn’t seen her since the confession.

“H-Hello, Sir Rio. Umm... Please take care of yourself.”

Despite seeming nervous, Sayo gave the brightest smile she could. In turn, Rio was also able to regain some of his ability to smile.

“Yes. You too, Sayo. Take care.”

“I-I’ll do my best. And, also... Sir Rio!” Sayo called Rio’s name with resolution.

“...What is it?” Rio tilted his head hesitantly.

“I’m going to do my best! I’ll do my best... So you do your best, too, Sir Rio!” Sayo said enthusiastically.

Rio’s eyes widened in confusion before he smiled in amusement. “...Yes. I’ll do my best. I’m very happy you came to see me off. Thank you very much.”

“I-It was nothing. I’m glad... Ahaha.” Sayo let out a breath of relief and smiled happily. She was almost moved to tears, but no tears of sadness spilled out.

“Aren’t you going to say anything, Shin?” Standing back beside them, Ruri turned the spotlight to Shin.

“Hmph. Well, take care, I guess. And you haven’t said anything either, Ruri.” Shin said bluntly.

“Ahaha, that’s because, y’know. I’ve already got my share of farewells in. Rio, make sure to visit if you have the time to come back. As often as possible, if you can,” Ruri said, flushing with embarrassment.

“Got it. I wonder... You might be married the next time we meet, Ruri,” Rio said, imagining the future.

“Ahaha, who knows. Oh, but if no one wants me as their bride, will you have me, Rio?” Ruri replied jokingly.

“...It’ll be fine. If it’s you, then I’m sure you’ll find someone wonderful to marry.” Rio evaded the question with a huff of laughter.

“Oh my, looks like I was rejected. Too bad. See you later, then, Rio.” Ruri shrugged with a small sigh and offered her hand out for Rio to shake.

“Yup, see you. I was really happy to be able to live like family with you, Ruri.” Rio returned Ruri’s handshake and nodded happily.

“We’re not like family, we are family. Even if we can’t tell anyone, you and I are cousins,” Ruri whispered in Rio’s ear.

“You’re right. Thank you, truly,” Rio said, smiling widely as he thanked Ruri.

Next, he addressed Yuba, who was standing nearby. “You, too. Thank you for everything.”

“Those should be my words. Like I said before, you’re welcome back here at any time. That’s why you must take care of yourself. Got it?” Yuba said with a huff of laughter on her lips.

“...Yes, thank you very much.” Rio bowed his head deeply, and Yuba looked around.

“Now! Is there anyone who has yet to say their goodbyes?” she asked.

“Have a good trip!”

“Be careful.”

“You can come back, but don’t forget the souvenirs.”

“I want alcohol!”

“Later!”

All the various voices of the village sounded off.

“...Doesn’t seem like it. All right, Rio. Have a safe journey!” Yuba cackled heartily and sent Rio off with cheer.

Rio bowed deeply one last time. “Okay everyone, I’ll be going now! I’ll make sure to bring back souvenirs for you!”

With those final words, Rio turned on his heel and waved with a smile, before walking out of the village as all the villagers loudly yelled their goodbyes.

Rio turned and waved his arms furiously as the distance between him and the village gradually widened.

It was the fall season of the year 999 of the Holy Era.

Epilogue: In A World Like This

The year was 1000 of the Holy Era.

One day, several months after Rio had left the Yagumo region... Somewhere in the world, someone had been waiting for that moment, as though it had been predicted.

Looks like it’s about time.

The Strahl region was reflected in their eyes. In the next moment, six pillars of light shot out of multiple points in the region, aiming straight up at the skies. The light pillars instantly tore through the heavens, overwhelming onlookers with their blinding light for some time.

However, the person in question simply observed the light with a blank expression.

Nothing’s changed from a thousand years ago. Even so, the world’s history is about to move. No... The chance of it moving has been birthed. Whether it changes, repeats, or stagnates like this...

Any further ahead than that was unknown to this person — therefore, they simply observed the now, and the future hereafter.

Oh? Seems like there are many lost children this time. Hm? This is...

Suddenly, they narrowed their eyes. No sooner than they did, their eyes opened in focus. A single human was reflected in their eyes.

◇◇◇

Meanwhile, after the six pillars of light had lost their glow, in the southeast area of the Strahl region, two girls and a boy stood isolated in a grass-covered field.

One of them was a high school student in her uniform, one was a middle school student in her school uniform, and one was a primary school student in his casual clothes — no one wore clothing appropriate for traveling in a grassy area.

The three children looked around at their surroundings in a daze. Their frozen expressions were understandable; the modern townscape they were surrounded by moments ago had completely disappeared, after all.

A grass field spread around them, with the only other things in sight being rocks, hills, and mountains, with no sign of anything man-made.

“...Where, is this?”

“...Don’t ask me.”

“Sorry. I wasn’t asking you — I was asking Miharu.”

The middle school girl and primary school boy went back and forth, not having yet accepted their reality. Shortly after, the two simultaneously looked up at the high school girl named Miharu.

“E-Erm, for now... L-Let’s check where we are on the smartphone.”

Miharu put on a smile to reassure the two and hurriedly took out her phone from her school bag. Then, with trembling hands, she pressed the button and started up the screen. “Out of range” was fruitlessly displayed at the corner of the screen.

◇◇◇

Meanwhile, elsewhere in the Strahl region at the exact same time...

Haruto.

...haru... ...-er...

...-ve ...them.

The oddly-familiar voice of a girl echoed inside Rio’s head.